<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Hack</string>
    <string name="web_client_id">98006081024-ut1ktdr07mkfk1l6qd7rlhpll0m8l3k8.apps.googleusercontent.com</string>
    <string name="title_activity_login_patient">LoginPatient</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_profile">Profile</string>

    <string name="Influenza">Common cold is one of the most commonly occurring during the monsoon season. It is highly contagious disease due to the spread of virus in the air which infects the upper respiratory tract and thus affects the nose and the throat. Symptoms involve runny or stuffy nose, body ache, throat irritation and soreness and fever. It is always advisable to consult a physician and get the required medicines prescribed for getting cured from the infection
The best way to prevent common cold is to have a healthy, balanced and nutritious diet regular which will develop the immune system of the body and improves the body resistance.
    </string>
    <string name="Cholera">Another most common and deadly bacterial disease that spreads during monsoon is “cholera” This disease is caused by contaminated food and water and also poor hygienic conditions .Common symptoms of cholera are severe diarrhoea with watery stool ’rice water stools” and vomiting which causes immediate water loss and muscle cramps. Diarrhoea can be so severe that it leads within hours to severe dehydration and electrolyte imbalance. A rapid dipstick test is available to determine the presence of V. cholera bacteria from stool sample
Cholera requires immediate treatment because the disease can cause death within hours. The goal is to replace lost fluids and electrolytes using a simple rehydration solution, oral rehydration salts (ORS). The ORS solution is available as a powder that can be reconstituted in boiled or bottled water. Antibiotics are not a necessary part of cholera treatment.
Preventive measures include providing clean drinking water, better sanitation, and better handwashing
    </string>
    <string name="Typhoid">“Typhoid” is another waterborne bacterial infection caused by bacteria called Salmonella. This disease is caused by contaminated food or drinking food or water contaminated with the faeces of an infected person.  Diagnosis is made by any blood, bone marrow or stool cultures and with the Widal test.
Symptoms of the diseases are prolonged high fever, severe abdomen pain, headache; vomits are common symptoms of this disease. The worst part is that the infection of this disease can remain in the gall bladder of the patient even after he/she is cured.
Preventive measures include providing clean drinking water, better sanitation, and better handwashing.
Treatments of typhoid include antibiotics such as azithromycin, fluoroquinolones or third generation cephalosporin.
    </string>
    <string name="HeptiA">Hepatitis A is a highly contagious liver infection caused by the hepatitis A virus. It is a waterborne viral infection is generally caused by contaminated drinking water or food with the stool of someone with the virus, it can spread through flies. Eating fruits, vegetables, or other foods that were contaminated during handling can cause spread of infection. The symptom of this disease is directly related to the inflammation of the liver that\'s caused by a virus.
Symptoms include, Jaundice (yellow eyes and skin, dark urine), stomach pain, Loss of appetite, Nausea, Fever, Diarrhoea and Fatigue. Blood tests are used to detect the presence of hepatitis A in your body.
No specific treatment exists for hepatitis A.. In most cases of hepatitis A, the liver heals within six months with no lasting damage .Management involves, Rest, treatment of nausea and rest to liver.
Practicing good hygiene, including washing hands frequently, is one of the best ways to protect against hepatitis A. Vaccines are available for people most at risk.
    </string>
    <string name="dengue">Dengue fever is a disease caused by a family of viruses that are transmitted by mosquitoes. It is spread by what\'s known as the tiger mosquito (Aedes Aegypti), which has black and white stripes and typically bites early in the morning or at dawn. Dengue goes by other names, including "break bone fever.
Symptoms of dengue fever include severe joint and muscle pain, swollen lymph nodes, headache, fever, exhaustion, and rash. Complication of dengue fever is called Dengue haemorrhagic fever (DHF). It is a specific syndrome that tends to affect children under 10 years of age. This complication of dengue causes abdominal pain, haemorrhage (bleeding), and circulatory collapse (shock).
There are no specific antibiotics or antiviral medication to treat it. For typical dengue, the treatment is concerned with relief of the symptoms and signs. Rest and fluid intake (oral rehydration) are important. Pain relievers such as aspirin and nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs should only be taken under a doctor's supervision because of the possibility of worsening bleeding complications. Pain killers can be given for headache and for joint and muscle pain (myalgia). Platelet count should be monitored through the course of the illness.  Sometimes hospitalization for dengue maybe advised depending upon the patient’s condition receive IV fluids.
    </string>
    <string name="dengue1">-As it\'s transmitted via mosquitoes, one should wear a strong insect repellent containing DEET to prevent getting bitten.</string>
    <string name="dengue2">-People should also wear full sleeve clothing when out in the day.</string>
    <string name="dengue3">- It is important to remember that the dengue mosquito usually bites only in the day time and breeds in clean, fresh water. So any water accumulation should be avoided.</string>
    <string name="malaria">One of the most common monsoon-related diseases, malaria, is caused by certain species of mosquitoes breeding in the dirty water. Since, there is a problem of water logging during the rainy season, mosquitoes get conducive conditions to breed .This disease is spread by Female Anopheles mosquito. Most deaths are caused by P. falciparum and is the most dangerous type of malaria also known as Cerebral malaria. Other forms of malaria are P. vivax, P. ovale, and P. malariae
Malaria is typically diagnosed by the microscopic examination of blood using blood films, or with antigen-based rapid diagnostic tests.
It is characterized by fever, body ache, chills, and sweating. If untreated, it can lead to complications like jaundice, severe anaemia or even liver and kidney failure. Malaria is treated with antimalarial medications successfully.
    </string>
    <string name="malaria1">•	Take an antimalarial drug as a precautionary measure in mosquito prone areas.</string>
    <string name="malaria2">•	Also take measures to prevent mosquito bites such as wearing full sleeve clothing.</string>
    <string name="malaria3">•	Application of antirepellant mosquito creams and Electronic mosquito repellent devices can be used during the monsoon season to avoid mosquito’s at home.</string>
    <string name="malaria4">•	Accumulation of dirty water must be kept in check to prevent malaria mosquito breeding.</string>
    <string name="malaria5">•	Insecticide-treated mosquito nets (ITNs) and indoor residual spraying (IRS) have been shown to be highly effective in preventing malaria in your neighbourhood and can reduce breeding of mosquitos also.</string>

    <string name="gastro">Gastroenteritis and food poisoning are quite common during the monsoon season, and the high humidity helps in the growth of disease-causing bacteria. The general symptoms of gastroenteritis are stomach cramps, nausea, vomiting or diarrhoea. Fever can develop and one may feel sense of malaise and weakness through the course of the illness.
It is very important that you keep yourself hydrated at all times and bland diet is recommended such as rice, curds, fruits such as banana, apple. Rice kanji water or coconut water is also good line of treatment for hydration. ORS is generally recommended. Course of treatment is mainly to prevent dehydration, control fever. Antibiotics are prescribed after evaluation of the condition of the patient. Antiprotozoal can also be prescribed accordingly.
    </string>
    <string name="gastro1">•	Try and avoid eating raw food like salads because it is difficult to ascertain whether they have been washed, cleaned and stored at the right temperature</string>
    <string name="gastro2">•	Avoid roadside food which may be made in contaminated water and trigger diarrhoea.</string>

    <string name="viralfever">Sudden weather change often causes viral fever characterized by fatigue, chills, body aches and fever. The illness is contagious and spreads through infection droplets in the air or by coming into physical contact with infected secretions. General duration of a viral fever lasts from 3 to 7 days, with the severity of the fever being the highest in the first three days..
 The general treatment  if side effects and symptoms using OTC drugs in consultation with their doctor, antihistamines, decongestants  and antipyretic drugs are usually recommended, Viral disease are generally self-limiting and generally do not need antibiotic unless there is a secondary infection.
</string>
    <string name="viralfever1">-One must ensure that they do not get wet in the rain or stay in wet clothes for a long period</string>
    <string name="viralfever2">-Wash their hands often</string>
    <string name="viralfever3">-Boost their immunity by eating Vitamin C rich foods and green leafy vegetables. They must also keep a distance from an infected person.</string>


    <string name="Tips1">•	Drink only clean water as a preventive measure against water borne diseases like typhoid, jaundice, gastroenteritis and diarrhoea which are common due to contamination of drinking water source. It is a good idea to drink only boiled water or water cleaned by a purifier.</string>
    <string name="Tips2">•	Use separate hand towels to avoid the transmission of disease causing bacteria.</string>
    <string name="Tips3">•	Cover your mouth and nose with a handkerchief while coughing or sneezing.</string>
    <string name="Tips4">•	Use mosquito repellents and nets as dengue transmitting mosquitoes usually bite during day time -either early morning or late evening, while those that cause malaria tend to bite at night.</string>
    <string name="Tips5">•	Keep your garments dry to avoid catching fungal skin infections.</string>
    <string name="Tips6">•	Consume freshly prepared food and avoid eating out as much as possible.</string>
    <string name="Tips7">•	Use hand sanitisers regularly.</string>


    <string name="facts1">•	Laughing is good for the heart and can increase blood flow by 20 percent.</string>
    <string name="facts2">•	Exercise will give you more energy, even when you’re tired.</string>
    <string name="facts3">•	Sitting and sleeping are great in moderation, but too much can increase your chances of an early death.</string>
    <string name="facts4">•	Learning a new language or playing a musical instrument gives your brain a boost.</string>
    <string name="facts5">•	Drinking coffee can reduce the risk of depression.</string>
    <string name="facts6">•	Yoga can boost your cognitive function and lowers stress.</string>
    <string name="facts7">•	Walking outside – or spending time in green space – can reduce negative thoughts and boost self-esteem.</string>
    <string name="facts8">•	Eating oatmeal provides a serotonin boost to calm the brain and improve your mood.</string>
    <string name="facts9">•	An apple a day does keep the doctor away. Apples can reduce levels of bad cholesterol to keep your heart healthy.</string>
    <string name="facts10">• The amino acid found in eggs can help improve your reflexes.</string>
    <string name="facts11">• Extra virgin olive oil is the healthiest fat on the planet.</string>
    <string name="facts12">• Vitamin D is as important as calcium in determining bone health, and most people don’t get enough of it.</string>
    <string name="facts13">• There are five main components of fitness: the body’s ability to use oxygen, muscular strength, endurance, flexibility and body composition.</string>
    <string name="facts14">• The body has more than 650 muscles.</string>
    <string name="facts15">• To lose one pound of fat, you need to burn roughly 3,500 calories.</string>
    <string name="facts16">• Walking at a fast pace for three hours or more at least one time a week, you can reduce your risk of heart disease by up to 65%.</string>
    <string name="facts17">• Even at rest, muscle is three times more efficient at burning calories than fat.</string>
    <string name="facts18">• Running is good for you. People who run 12-18 miles a week have a stronger immune system and can increase their bone mineral density.</string>
    <string name="facts19">• Stretching increases the blood flow to your muscles and helps avoid injuries.</string>
    <string name="facts20">• Drinking at least five glasses of water a day can reduce your chances of suffering from a heart attack by 40%.</string>
    <string name="facts21">• Consuming water helps the body maintain its natural pH balance. </string>
    <string name="facts22">• Kidneys filter your blood up to 300 times a day and need water to function optimally. </string>
    <string name="facts23">• A lack of water can cause a range of problems, such as asthma, allergy and migraines.</string>
    <string name="facts24">• Your muscles and joints require water in order to stay energized, lubricated and healthy. </string>
    <string name="facts25">• Brushing teeth too soon after eating or drinking can soften the tooth enamel, especially if you’ve just been eating or drinking acidic foods.</string>
    <string name="facts26">• Cardio exercise before breakfast can burn more fat. </string>
    <string name="facts27">• Breathing deeply in moments of stress, or anytime during the day, brings many benefits such as better circulation, decreased anxiety and reduced blood pressure. </string>
    <string name="facts28">• On average, there are more bacteria per square inch in a kitchen sink than the bathroom. </string>
    <string name="facts29">• During an allergic reaction your immune system is responding to a false alarm that it perceives as a threat. </string>
    <string name="facts30">• The eye muscles are the most active in the body, moving more than 100,000 times a day!</string>
    <string name="facts31">• Humans can cough at 60 miles an hour and sneezes can be 100 miles an hour – which is faster than the average car!</string>
    <string name="facts32">• The soles of your feet contain more sweat glands and nerve endings per square inch than anywhere else on your body. </string>
    <string name="facts33">• People need 8+ hours of sleep per night for their bodies to function properly. </string>
    <string name="facts34">• Physical activity like aerobic exercise (walking, running), muscle-strengthening (weight-lifting), bone-strengthening (jumping rope), and balance and stretching activities (yoga, pilates, dancing) are especially beneficial to a healthy body.</string>
    <string name="facts35">• Breakfast is the most important meal of the day because it feeds your body and mind with the necessary nutrients and energy to function throughout the day. </string>
    <string name="facts36">• Over 30% of cancer could be prevented by avoiding tobacco and alcohol, having a healthy diet and physical activity.</string>
    <string name="facts37">• Sitting At A Desk Can Increase Death Risk By Almost 50 Percent.</string>


    <!-- DISEASES IN PARTICULAR STATE -->

    <string name="ArunP1">Use of untreated spring water and surface water brought to the villages by gravity fed pipes for drinking to be the major cause. The problem was compounded by lack of awareness about the cause of diarrhoeal diseases, entric fever, hepatitis, about ORS home management of diarrhoea in infants and children which resulted in considerable mortality due to diarrhoeal diseases. </string>
    <string name="ArunP2">Malaria is highly endemic in Arunachal Pradesh. The API was 63.61 in east Siang during 1990. Lack of health infrastructure, roads for outreach and difficulties in programme implementation are the causes of high morbidity and mortality due to malaria. </string>
    <string name="ArunP3">Tuberculosis continues to cause significant morbidity and mortality, about 7% of deaths being caused by tuberculosis. </string>
    <string name="ArunP4">Leprosy to be a significant cause of morbidity in the state. Lohit and Dibang districts had a prevalence rate of 1 per 1000 population. Upper and lower Subansini East and West Kameng and Changlang had prevalence of 1-3 per 1000 population. East Siang and west Siang had prevalence of 4-6 per 1000 population. </string>
    <string name="ArunP5">Acute respiratory infections among children causing high morbidity and mortality was a major problem. The cause of ARI was reported to be indoor fires kept burning all through the night at homes for warmth. F. Goiter: Goiter is a major problem in the State. The estimated prevalence of Iodine deficiency disorders in the population was 14.9%.</string>
    <string name="ArunP6">Arunachal Pradesh border with Myanmar and a tradition of opium addiction among few tribes and limited scale of HIV screening place Arunachal Pradesh at risk of IV drug abuse and HIV-AIDS.</string>


    <string name="Assam1">Poor habitat and improper sanitation are other major problems in the rural areas. Untreated drinking water from open sources like ponds, wells, rivers etc. are the major causes of various water borne diseases like Cholera, Diarrhea, Dysentery etc. Contamination of drinking water sources in rural areas may be due to the use of pesticides and chemical fertilizers and animal dung in the agricultural field and improper sanitation. In Assam most of the village people are deprived of proper health care services as the dispensaries and health care centers are not at easy reach. Distribution of free medicine including the life saving medicines and amp; saline are not adequatey provided to the poor rural people, many of whom are suffering from indoor air pollution due to the use of biomass fuel.  It is common for village people to use wood and bamboo and sometimes-dried animal dung and plants as fuel for cooking. Contaminated drinking water and improper sanitation is the primary cause for various water borne diseases. Diarrhea, Dysentery, Cholera and Gastroenteritis are the major water borne diseases of Assam. Diarrhea, Dysentery, Cholera, Typhoid, Hepatitis and E. coli are dominant during the monsoon season when protozoan and bacteria are rampant and overflow from sewage. Mosquito-borne diseases, including malaria, Japanese encephalitis (JE), lymphatic filariasis and dengue, are major public health concerns in the north-eastern state of Assam, deterring equitable socioeconomic and industrial development. Among these, malaria and JE are the predominant infections and are spread across the state. The incidence of malaria is, however, gradually receding, with a consistent decline in cases over the past few years, although entry and spread of artemisinin-resistant Plasmodium falciparum remains a real threat in the country. JE, formerly endemic in upper Assam, is currently spreading fast across the state, with confirmed cases and a high case-fatality rate affecting all ages. Lymphatic filariasisis is prevalent but its distribution is confined to a few districts and disease transmission is steadily declining. Dengue has recently invaded the state, with a large concentration of cases in Guwahati city that are spreading to suburban areas. Control of these diseases requires robust disease surveillance and integrated vector management on a sustained basis, ensuring universal coverage of evidence-based key interventions based on sound epidemiological data.</string>


    <string name="Nagaland">Nagaland Government is aware of the following major health problems causing morbidity and mortality in the State. Gastroenteritis, diarrhoeal diseases, worm infestation, skin diseases, respiratory diseases, urinary tract infection among women, tuberculosis, malaria, Jeneephetitis, heart diseases, cancer, leprosy are the common cause of morbidity and mortality. Intravenous drug abuse has become a major problem among youth. HIV is an emerging problem among youths. In a survey of youths who were IV drug addicts, 13.5% were HIV positive together with high prevailing rates of venereal disease. HIV transmission to females of reproductive age and there-by to infants is a major health risk. Diarrhoeal diseases, whooping cough, fever with rigor and parasitic infestation were the common illness among children.</string>
    <string name="Nagaland1">There has been a rapid increase in asthma cases in Nagaland. 4343 cases in 1998-99. This is very much higher than the all India cases of 1966. It is a chronic respiratory disease troubles breathing and chest constriction.</string>
    <string name="Nagaland2">The over all prevalence of TB in India is 390 cases per 100000 population, whereas in Nagaland it is 1723 cases per 100000 population. The prevalence of medically treated TB in Nagaland is 1546 per 100000 population whereas the all India average is 307 per 100000. Tuberculosis is a highly critical problem disease in Nagaland.</string>
    <string name="Nagaland3">Jaundice symptoms discolouration of eyes, skin, fever, liver enlargement, abdominal pain. It spreads due to scarcity of potable water and sanitation. The prevalence of Jaundice in Nagaland is 6972 cases per 100000 population, whereas the all- India average of 1225 cases/100000. The prevalence is very much high in Nagaland.</string>
    <string name="Nagaland4">Malaria prevalence rate in Nagaland is 14447 cases per 100000 population compared to the all India average of 2156 cases/100000 population. Malaria is a big problem in Nagaland.</string>


    <string name="Manipur1">The prevalence of Asthma is lower in Manipur than the all India average. But compare to Nagaland the neighbouring border state is also lower. In Nagaland the prevalence rate is 5729 per 100000 population. </string>
    <string name="Manipur2">Tuberculosis which is also resurgent worldwide. According to NFHS-2 the over all prevalence of Tuberculosis in India is 544 per 100000 population. But in Manipur the prevalence rate is 1107 per 100000 population which is more than the double or much higher than their all India average prevalence. The over all prevalence of Medically treated tuberculosis in India is 432 per 100000 population compare to Manipur which is 1020 per 100000 population. Medically treated tuberculosis is more reliable to know the prevalence of active tuberculosis.</string>
    <string name="Manipur3">The prevalence of Jaundice in India average is 1361 per 100000 population where as the prevalence rate in Manipur is 1728 per 100000 population much higher than the all India level. People living in rural area were some what more likely to have suffered from Jaundice than those living in urban areas. The prevalence of Jaundice was highest in age group 0-14 years followed by age group 15-59 years. </string>
    <string name="Manipur4">The prevalence of Malaria in all India average is 3697 per 100000 population, but in Manipur it is 1995 per 100000 population which is much lower than the national average where has in Nagaland the same north eastern state which is 16166 per 100000 population. Rural residents are almost twice as likely to suffer from malaria. 4254 per 100000 population as are urban residents 2156 per 100000 population. Malaria, Jaundice and Tuberculosis is most common in north eastern states. North eastern states have a higher prevalence of all these diseases than the national average. Asthma is most common in north eastern states than the prevalence rate of all India average.</string>
    <string name="Manipur5">It is basically acute respiratory infection fever and diarrhoea. Pneumonia is a major cause of illness among infants and children and leading cause of childhood mortality throughout the world.</string>


    <string name="Mizoram1">Due to lack of potable water diarrhoeal diseases poses a major problem to the population. The overall morbidity trends indicate high morbidity in the population. Table 2 shows the morbidity of the state.</string>
    <string name="Mizoram2">The prevalence of Asthma is lower in Mizoram than the all India average of 2468 cases per 100000. But compare to Assam the neighbouring border state is also lower. The prevalence of Asthma is considerably higher in rural areas than urban area. </string>
    <string name="Mizoram3">Tuberculosis which is also resurgent world wide is an infectious disease. The overall prevalence of tuberculosis in India is 544 per 100000 population. In Mizoram the prevalence rate is 1063 per 100000 population which is much higher than the national average. Except Assam the all other north eastern states prevalence rate is much higher than the national average. </string>
    <string name="Mizoram4">In Mizoram 3155 persons suffered per 100000 population. The prevalence rate for India is 1361. Mizoram is much higher than the national average and in Nagaland it is 5348/100000.</string>
    <string name="Mizoram5">The prevalence of Malaria in Mizoram is 7359 per 100000 population. The national average is 3697/100000 population. Mizoram is much higher prevalence state compare to national average. In Meghalaya it is 16656 per 100000 population. Rural people are more likely to suffer from Malaria than urban people. The prevalence of Malaria is higher in males than females. Malaria, Jaundice and Tuberculosis is most common in north eastern states. North eastern states have a higher prevalence of all these diseases than the national average. Asthma is most common in north eastern states than the prevalence rate of all India average. </string>
    <string name="Mizoram6">It is  acute respiratory infection, fever, diarrhoea in children. ARI primarily pneumonia is a major cause of illness among infants and children and leading cause of childhood mortality throughout the world. Early diagnosis and treatment can prevent a large number of ARI (Pneumonia) deaths. 19% of children under age 3 years in India suffered from ARI. In Mizoram 11.2% children suffered from ARI which is very much lower than the national average of 19.3%. Four states of north eastern region. Arunachal Pradesh, Manipur, Meghalaya and Sikkim the prevalence rate of ARI is very much high 25.4%, 26.9%, 28.8% and 30.0% respectively more than the national average 19.3%. </string>
    <string name="Mizoram7">The prevalence of fever national average is 29.5%. The prevalence in north eastern states varies from 28.4% in Assam to 41.2% in Meghalaya. The prevalence rate in Mizoram is 35.9% which is much higher than the national average.</string>


    <string name="Tripura">Major problems are Diarrhoeal diseases, parasitic infestation, infective hepatitis, entric fever and other waterborne diseases (related to non-potable drinking water and sanitation). Malnutrition among children, anaemia, malaria, and respiratory diseases. Diarrhoeal diseases and entric fever (group of diseases) was the leading cause of mortality in the state, 47.7% rural population not covered with potable water 24.6% partially covered. High endemic levels of diarroheal diseases together with epidemics cause much of the work load for the health services, leaving very little time to other activities such as MCH and Family Welfare.</string>


    <string name="Meghalya1">1. The primary causes of morbidity and mortality of the people of Meghalaya are grouped as follow: Diseases due to different environmental precursors:</string>
    <string name="Meghalya2">a) Unsafe water, poor sanitation: Diarrhoea and gastroenteritis, hepatitis, worm infection.</string>
    <string name="Meghalya3">b) Hill climate, poor housing etc: Diseases of respiratory systems, pneumonia, pulmonary tuberculosis, cough, etc.</string>
    <string name="Meghalya4">c) Prevalence of pests: Malaria. </string>
    <string name="Meghalya5">d) Vehicular accidents and trauma. </string>
    <string name="Meghalya6">2. Diseases related to specific population groups and different occupational activities:</string>
    <string name="Meghalya7">a) New born and schoolchildren: Diphtheria, whooping cough, measles, etc.</string>
    <string name="Meghalya8">b) Specific diseases- Leprosy, peptic ulcer, influenza </string>
    <string name="Meghalya9">c) Nutritional deficiency: Anaemia (related to diarrhoea, Malaria and maternal causes.)</string>
    <string name="Meghalya10">d) Alcohol related: Cardiac and liver diseases, cancer, etc.</string>


    <string name="Sikkim1">Gallstones are common in Sikkim and North Bengal among dyspeptics. A majority of patients are of normal weight. The disease occurs a decade earlier in women, most of whom have only up to two children. The most common presenting symptoms were flatulence, dyspepsia, epigastric pain, and pain in the right hypochondrium. Some patients complained of nausea. The most common gallstones were mixed stones with 81.12%, followed by cholesterol stones with 13.29% and pigment stones with 5.59%.</string>
    <string name="Sikkim2">The pattern of skin disease is a consequence of poverty, malnutrition, overcrowding, poor hygiene, illiteracy, and social backwardness in many parts of India. The evaluation for skin disorders forms an important component of primary health care practice and the prevalence of certain skin diseases in children can reflect status of health, hygiene, and personal cleanliness of a community. The evaluation for skin disorders is an important component of primary health care practice for all, including children.</string>
    <string name="Sikkim3">The common parasitic diseases affecting the respiratory system in this population were hydatid cyst, chronic schistosomiasis, strongyloides stercoralis and the pulmonary phases of nematode infestations causing acute eosinophilic pneumonia. Pulmonary disease such as Bronchial Asthma is a psychosomatic disorder vulnerable to exacerbations precipitated by psychological factors. Respiratory diseases are often found associated with infections, infestations, air pollution, tobacco smoking and environmental tobacco exposure. The indoor pollutants such as paints, house hold cleaning devices, allergens, house dust, mites, fungi, dampness, humidity, congestion and combustion fumes from cooking fuel (wood, coal, kerosene) are likely to cause respiratory illnesses.</string>


    <string name="Kerela">Flood-hit Kerala, always grappling with vector-borne diseases such as dengue and chikungunya, now also faces the threat of water-borne illnesses, with public health experts warning of an outbreak of cholera, typhoid, hepatitis and leptospirosis. Its symptoms include fever, chills, abdominal pains, vomiting and diarrhoea. However, it should not be an epidemic but the situation is very serious. Exposure to floodwater can increase the risk of skin rashes, ear, nose and throat problems and conjunctivitis. Leptospirosis is a bacterial disease transmitted mainly through water or soil contaminated by the urine of infected animals. The state also saw cases of chicken pox with one death. Also,viral Hepatitis A was also common. From January to 1 September 2018, Kerala has seen 788 cases of leptospirosis with 36 deaths, 21,915 chicken pox cases with 15 deaths, and 141 cases of scrub typhus with two deaths. During the same period last year, there were 1,408 leptospirosis cases with 80 deaths, and 340 scrub typhus cases with five deaths. Doxycycline tablets in flood-hit areas to prevent leptospirosis was given and separate wards for chicken pox cases were created.</string>


    <string name="Karnataka1">Heart and sensory organ diseases affect Karnataka the most. They are prone to ischemic heart disease, sensory organ diseases (eyes, ears). Many people suffer from diphtheria. Diphtheria (dif-THEER-e-uh) is a serious bacterial infection usually affecting the mucous membranes of your nose and throat. Diphtheria typically causes a sore throat, fever, swollen glands and weakness. But the hallmark sign is a sheet of thick, gray material covering the back of your throat, which can block your airway, causing you to struggle for breath. Symptoms of diphtheria are thick, gray membrane covering your throat and tonsils, A sore throat and hoarseness, Swollen glands (enlarged lymph nodes) in your neck, Difficulty breathing or rapid breathing, Nasal discharge, fever and chills. In Karnataka poor provisioning of adequate drinking water is compounded by continued depletion of ground water table and presence of toxic minerals in drinking water. There is a need to increase coverage of Individual Household Latrines (IHHL), besides separate toilet facility for girls in schools. Usage of toilets will not sustain without provision of water supply. Thus, there is a need for convergence between water supply and sanitation schemes during design and implementation. During the year 2015, following are eight leading cause groups of deaths constituting around 86.98 per cent of total deaths:</string>
    <string name="Karnataka2">1. Diseases of circulatory system </string>
    <string name="Karnataka3">2. Injury, poisoning and certain other consequences of external causes</string>
    <string name="Karnataka4">3. Certain infectious and parasitic diseases</string>
    <string name="Karnataka5">4. Diseases of the respiratory system </string>
    <string name="Karnataka6">5. Neoplasm </string>
    <string name="Karnataka7">6. Diseases of the digestive system </string>


    <string name="TamilNadu1">Malaria is an acute parasitic illness caused by Plasmodium falciparum or Plasmodium vivax. Mosquitoes, of which there are 9 major species, transmit malaria in India. At the time of independence, there were an estimated 75 million malaria cases and 0.8 million deaths annually. GOI launched the National Malaria Control Programme (NMCP) in 1953. DDT spraying resulted in a sharp decline in the incidence of malaria in all areas under spray. In 1958, NMCP was converted to the National Malaria Eradication Programme (NMEP) with a view to eradicate malaria from the country. The areas vulnerable to malaria are largely tribal, difficult, remote, forested and forest fringe inaccessible areas with operational difficulties. The high transmission areas are the North Eastern States and largely tribal areas of Andhra Pradesh, Chhattisgarh, Gujarat, Jharkhand, Madhya Pradesh, Maharashtra, Odisha and Rajasthan.</string>
    <string name="TamilNadu2">Lymphatic Filariasis is a serious debilitating and incapacitating disease. The transmission of filaria is through mosquitoes called Culex quinquefasciatus. This disease has been reported from over 250 districts in 20 States and UTs wherein over 500 million people live. The disease is targeted for Global Elimination by 2020 through annual Mass Day Administration (MDA) of single dose of anti-filarial drug. In this context, a pilot project on single dose annual mass DEC drug administration was undertaken during 1997 in 13 districts of 7 endemic states, covering a population of about 41 million. By 2003, 31 districts were brought under MDA.</string>
    <string name="TamilNadu3">Dengue fever is a viral disease, which is transmitted by the Aedes aegypti mosquitoes. The Aedes mosquitoes breed in clean water in man made containers such as water coolers, discarded tyres, disposable cups, flower vases and other water storage containers. The first out break of Dengue fever/DHF was reported from Kolkata in 1963. All the four serotypes of dengue are prevalent in India.</string>
    <string name="TamilNadu4">Chikungunya is a debilitating non-fatal viral illness which has occurred in outbreak form in India during 2006 after a gap of 32 years. It resembles dengue fever. It is caused by Chikungunya virus. It is spread by the bite of female Aedes mosquitoes, primarily Aedes aegypti.</string>
    <string name="TamilNadu5">Japanese Encephalitis is an acute viral illness with high case fatality and long term complications. The vector breeds in large paddy fields and similar large water bodies. The vector is an outdoor rester and feeder. The disease has acquired serious magnitude in the states of Uttar Pradesh, Andhra Pradesh, West Bengal, Assam, Tamil Nadu, Karnataka, Kerala, Bihar, Goa, and Haryana. There is no specific treatment for JE. Efforts were made by states and Govt of India to contain JE outbreaks by instituting various public heath measures including selective JE vaccination. </string>
    <string name="TamilNadu6">Kala-azar is a parasitic disease caused by Leishmania donovani transmitted by sandflies Phlebotomus argentipes. The disease is prevalent among socio-economically poorer sections of the society living in rural areas. The disease is chronic and if not treated, leads to death. Kala-azar is endemic in Bihar, Jharkhand, West Bengal and parts of Uttar Pradesh. The Central Government initiated Kala-azar control Programme from 1990-91 incorporating assistance for procurement of insecticides and anti-leishmanial drugs. Indoor Residual Spraying with DDT for vector control, complete treatment of patients as well as intensive social mobilization is being stressed upon. Govt. of India has accelerated the Kala-azar elimination by taking the following renewed efforts.</string>
    <string name="TamilNadu7">Tuberculosis is a major public health problem in India. India accounts for one-fifth of the global TB incidence and is estimated to have the highest number of active TB cases amongst all the countries of the World. Every year there are approximately 18 lakh new cases in the country of which approximately 8 lakh are new smear positive and therefore infectious. Each sputum positive case if not treated, on an average, infects 10-15 persons in a year. Two persons die from TB in India every three minutes more than 1,000 people every day.</string>


    <string name="AndP1">Malaria followed by TB affects the largest number of people in the state. While malaria is found across the state, endemic malaria zones are associated with the hilly, forested tracts covering Srikakulam, Vizianagaram, Vishakapatnam, Khammam, and Adilabad. These five districts are also endemic to plasmodium falciparum (PF) malaria (brain fever), a more virulent type of malaria with high death rate. These districts including the northern parts of the Godavari districts are characterized by high Adivasi populations and poor health facilities in the ‘Agency’ areas. Of the other diseases shown on the map, filaria is endemic to the coastal districts with East and West Godavari, Srikakulam, Vizianagaram and Khammam reporting most cases. The earlier pattern of vector borne diseases prevalent in regions of higher rainfall and dense vegetation is changing. Japanese encephalitis and dengue cases in AP are today also found in large numbers in urban pockets (Hyderabad) and the Rayalseema and Telangana districts. Tuberculosis does not reveal any marked spatial preference, is reported across the state, though Prakasam, Adilabad, Anantapur, Khammam and Vizianagaram have a higher incidence. HIV prevalence which is linked to high TB incidence is noted in the coastal districts of Prakasam, East and West Godavari and Guntur. Incidence of leprosy is higher in the interior districts compared to coastal Andhra, with Kurnool, Mahbubnagar, Adilabad, Srikakulam and Vizianagaram reporting most cases. Water related diseases are a serious health problem in AP through the year and particularly, during the rainy season. Diarrhoea cases are high and reported from all districts, both urban and rural. Gastroenteritis epidemics are common during the monsoon months in Adilabad, Srikakulam, Vizianagaram, Nizamabad, Anantpur and Mahbubnagar. Fluorosis is a major health issue in large parts of the state, with Nalgonda and Mahbubnagar the worst affected. Viral hepatitis/jaundice cases are on the rise with Hyderabad and Ranga Reddy districts showing the largest number.</string>


    <string name="Telengana">For Telangana, the challenge is of tackling fluorosis and Andhra, especially, its two regions of Srikakulam and East Godavari, is still dealing with filariasis. Apart from these, both the states, like any other Indian state, also have to constantly focus on dealing with growing challenges from ailments like dengue, tuberculosis, malaria and seasonal flu other than the usual non-communicable diseases like hypertension, diabetes and cancer. Telangana has been dealing with the challenge of fluorosis for over 60 years. This is specifically a major problem in Nalgonda. This semi-arid region is known for its groundwater having higher than normal fluoride concentration. Intake of excess fluoride, most commonly through drinking water, can cause Fluorosis. It is a condition that affects teeth and bones. Moderate amounts lead to dental effects, but long-term intake in large amounts (typically for periods five years and more) can lead to potentially severe skeletal problems. Studies have pointed to some of the remedial measures planned in the region including providing piped water from the Krishna river but providing these to remote affected villages is still a long-term challenge that will need more time and capital. Experts have suggested the need to explore groundwater treatment technologies. In Telangana, especially in some of its coastal regions, the challenge is slightly different. It is about eradicating filariasis or lymphatic filariasis, as some would prefer to call it. It is a problem that has tended to be more prevalent in the Srikakulam and East Godavari regions of the state and has been known for several decades now. It is an infection that occurs when filarial parasites are transmitted to human from mosquito bites. These are usually in areas that are waterlogged and where there is stagnation of water. When these parasites are transmitted to humans and result in swelling (lymphoedema) of legs usually and commonly called  Elephantiasis - a painful, disfiguring swelling of the legs in the late stages of the disease. These regions of Andhra apart from other locations like parts of Kerala, have been coping with this disease for years now in India, which is among the 10 countries globally, which in all, according to the World Health Organisation (WHO), together make up for bulk of people affected by this ailment.A major part of the solution in creating awareness and as pointed out by global entities like the WHO, elimination of lymphatic filariasis is possible by stopping the spread of the infection. Large-scale treatment involves a single dose of two medicines given annually to an entire at-risk population and includes medicines like albendazole (400 mg) together with ivermectin (150-200 mcg/kg) or with diethylcarbamazine citrate (6 mg/kg). This treatment is generally referred to as preventive chemotherapy.</string>


    <string name="Bihar">Although demographic improvements have been noted in the past years, the incidence of various diseases remains high and socioeconomic status low in Bihar. Protein-energy malnutrition, nutritional anemia and blindness are common. Safe drinking water and sanitary facilities are still not available to a large number of people. Furthermore, a number of communicable diseases are prevalent in the country. This is exemplified in the Kala-azar or visceral leishmaniasis epidemic in 1992, which reported 75,523 cases and 1417 deaths. Kala-azar cases have started rising again since 1996, and it is estimated that there might be another epidemic in the first decade of the 21st century if the situation is allowed to continue. Other infectious diseases, which threaten the health situation in Bihar, are malaria, tuberculosis, leprosy, and HIV/AIDS. Moreover, population and decadal growth rate have more than doubled over the last 40 years. Maternal mortality remains very high, but survival chances of children have increased due to immunization and other programs. In general, it was demonstrated that the present health situation in Bihar is a matter of grave concern, and requires an urgent solution. Also, one disease common is Encephalitis. Encephalitis is an inflammation of the brain tissue. Once the virus enters inside the blood, it starts migrating to the brain tissues and multiplies itself into numbers. As soon as the signal reaches to our immune system, it generates a response to it in the form of inflamed brain or we can say swelled up brain. When this self-generated response and the infection combines, this leads to viral encephalitis and it majorly affects the spinal cord and our central nervous system causing damage to the brain cells through virus-infected blood vessels.</string>


    <string name="Chhattisgarh">The population in Chattisgarh suffer from Asthma, 11% from malaria, 1% from Jaundice and the prevalence of tuberculosis 0.6% and medically treated TB 0.5% in marginally higher than average India percentage of 0.5 and 0.4. The prevalence of Tuberculosis, Jaundice and Malaria is much higher in rural areas than urban areas. The prevalence of Asthma is the same in urban and rural areas. Men are more likely than women to suffer from each of the diseases. The changing profile of Chhattisgarh, from a backward state to a developing one, is having it’s adverse impact on the lifestyle and the health of the people too, as nearly 10.2 lakh people in the state suffer from chronic illness like diabetes, hypertension, asthma and arthritis. Cholera is transmitted through contaminated water or food and can rapidly lead to severe dehydration and death if left untreated. The symptoms of cholera were evident among patients in the affected district, said an ayurveda doctor on condition of anonymity. Since people in naxal-affected interior villages do not have access to clean drinking water from borewells, they drink contaminated water leading to the disease. The state of Chhattisgarh today faces several challenges in improving the health status of its people. The on-going problems of maternal and child mortality, communicable diseases, and HIV/AIDS pandemic still need greater interventions/support from the already overburdened health systems. In addition, the public health challenges include the escalating burden of chronic noncommunicable diseases. One of the emerging disease in Chattisgarh is sickle cell - a hereditary disease affecting the red blood cells. And is more prevalent among lower castes, such as the Kurmi and Sahu. Sickle cell damages the haemoglobin, a protein in the red blood cells, affecting their capacity to carry oxygen, and patients can suffer from anaemia, jaundice, body pain, pneumonia and repeated infections that may result in paralysis. The sickle-shaped RBC [red blood cells] face erratic movement in blood vessels. This stops blood carrying haemoglobin to reach to cells fast enough, thus resulting in severe pain or damage to affected areas.If not treated on time, it can cause death among children. And even when treated it can shorten life expectancy by at least 20 years.</string>


    <string name="WestBengal">The diseases may be classified in different ways. The diseases and infections which spread from one person to another very easily and rapidly through direct or indirect contact are known as Communicable or Infectious or Contagious diseases while the diseases which do not spread through contact are termed as Non-communicable diseases. The Communicable diseases can further be classified on the basis of their medium of transmission—Air-borne, Water-borne, Vector-borne diseases and Blood-borne diseases. The prevalence of all these category of diseases is observed among child population. Besides, there are some nutritional deficiency related disorders which are also observed in the vulnerable group of population. These may be grouped under the Non-communicable category of diseases. Diseases may also be classed on the basis of their areal expansion and frequency of occurrence. The unusual occurrence of a disease among a community in a definite region with specific health conditions clearly in ‘excess of expected occurrence’ is known as an Epidemic disease. Some use the term ‘outbreak’ for a small usually localized epidemic in the interest of minimizing public alarm unless the number of incidences is indeed very large. The epidemic diseases include the waterborne diseases of diarrhoea and dysentery as well as cholera which spread through consumption of contaminated food and water. It incorporates certain air-borne infections like small pox and chicken pox which have been compressed over time by administering vaccinations. The constant presence of a disease or an infectious agent among a population group within a definite geographical area without importation from outside is called an Endemic. The disease may have usual or expected frequency of occurrence. For instance the district of South 24 Parganas in West Bengal has been an endemic zone for the cholera disease. The term ‘hyper-endemic’ expresses that the disease is constantly present with a high incidence and prevalence rate and affects every age group Chapter-V: Childhood Diseases and Illness in Districts of West Bengal 158 equally. An endemic disease may often culminate into an epidemic provided the conditions are favourable for its outbreak on a massive scale. For instance the vectorborne diseases like malaria and dengue fever affects a chunk of population during the monsoon and post-monsoon seasons. In case of sporadic diseases, the cases occur irregularly and haphazardly from time to time and these are infrequent in character. The cases are so few and separated widely in space and time that they neither show any connection with each other nor focus on a recognizable common source of infection. This group of diseases include the poliomyelitis, tetanus and meningococcal meningitis. An epidemic usually affecting a large proportion of the population occurring over a wide geographic area, such as an entire nation or a part of the continent, is termed as a Pandemic disease. Influenza pandemics were prevalent till 1950s in India while Ebola pandemic has affected Africa in 2014. Vast stretches of the Asian landmass is often affected by Bird Flu while Swine Flu.. The virus was carried to Ravenna in Italy by a person who had recently visited the affected areas of India. The outbreak in Europe was unexpected, since the region’s temperate climate was thought to provide a barrier against the invasion of Aedes aegypti type of mosquitoes which transmit chikungunya virus. The airborne diseases like acute respiratory infection, pneumonia, diphtheria, measles, tetanus neonatorum, paediatric tuberculosis, poliomyelitis and whooping cough affect children. Acute Respiratory Infection (ARI) is a typical air-borne disease which causes inflammation of the respiratory tract from nose to alveoli. The symptoms of ARI include common cold, pharyngitis, epiglottitis and pneumonia. The clinical features observed are running nose, cough, sore throat, breathing problem and fever.</string>


    <string name="Goa1">Pre-existing medical conditions and accidental injury (especially traffic accidents) account for most life-threatening problems. Becoming ill in some way, however, is common. Fortunately, most travellers’ illnesses can be prevented with some common-sense behaviour or treated with a well-stocked travellers’ medical kit – however, never hesitate to consult a doctor while on the road, as self-diagnosis can be hazardous</string>
    <string name="Goa2">This is a serious and potentially deadly disease. Before you travel, seek expert advice according to your itinerary (rural areas are especially risky) and on medication and side effects.</string>
    <string name="Goa3">Malaria is caused by a parasite transmitted by the bite of an infected mosquito. The most important symptom of malaria is fever, but general symptoms, such as headache, diarrhoea, cough or chills, may also occur. Diagnosis can only be properly made by taking a blood sample.</string>
    <string name="Goa4">Two strategies should be combined to prevent malaria: mosquito avoidance and antimalarial medications. Most people who catch malaria are taking inadequate or no antimalarial medication.</string>
    <string name="Goa5">Travellers are advised to prevent mosquito bites by taking these steps:</string>
    <string name="Goa6">1. Use a DEET-based insect repellent on exposed skin. Wash this off at night – as long as you are sleeping under a mosquito net. Natural repellents such as citronella can be effective, but must be applied more frequently than products containing DEET.</string>
    <string name="Goa7">2. Sleep under a mosquito net impregnated with pyrethrin. Choose accommodation with proper screens and fans (if not air-conditioned).</string>
    <string name="Goa8">3. Impregnate clothing with pyrethrin in high-risk areas.</string>
    <string name="Goa9">4. Wear long sleeves and trousers in light colours.</string>
    <string name="Goa10">5. Use mosquito coils.</string>
    <string name="Goa11">6. Spray your room with insect repellent before going out for your evening meal.</string>
    <string name="Goa12">There are a variety of medications available:</string>
    <string name="Goa13">1. Chloroquine and Paludrine combination Limited effectiveness in many parts of South Asia. Common side effects include nausea (40% of people) and mouth ulcers.</string>
    <string name="Goa14">2. Doxycycline (daily tablet) A broad-spectrum antibiotic that helps prevent a variety of tropical diseases, including leptospirosis, tick-borne disease and typhus. Potential side effects include photosensitivity (a tendency to sunburn), thrush (in women), indigestion, heartburn, nausea and interference with the contraceptive pill. More serious side effects include ulceration of the oesophagus – take your tablet with a meal and a large glass of water, and never lie down within half an hour of taking it. It must be taken for four weeks after leaving the risk area.</string>
    <string name="Goa15">3. Lariam (mefloquine) This weekly tablet suits many people. Serious side effects are rare but include depression, anxiety, psychosis and seizures. Anyone with a history of depression, anxiety, other psychological disorders or epilepsy should not take Lariam. It is considered safe in the second and third trimesters of pregnancy. Tablets must be taken for four weeks after leaving the risk area.</string>
    <string name="Goa16">4. Malarone A combination of atovaquone and proguanil. Side effects are uncommon and mild, most commonly nausea and headache. It is the best tablet for scuba divers and for those on short trips to high-risk areas. It must be taken for one week after leaving the risk area.</string>
    <string name="Goa17">Avian Flu ‘Bird flu’ or Influenza A (H5N1) is a subtype of the type A influenza virus. Contact with dead or sick birds is the principal source of infection and bird-to-human transmission does not easily occur. Symptoms include high fever and flu-like symptoms with rapid deterioration, leading to respiratory failure and death in many cases. Immediate medical care should be sought if bird flu is suspected. Check www.who.int/en/or www.avianinfluenza.com.au.</string>
    <string name="Goa18">Dengue Fever This mosquito-borne disease is becoming increasingly problematic, especially in the cities. As there is no vaccine available it can only be prevented by avoiding mosquito bites at all times. Symptoms include high fever, severe headache and body ache and sometimes a rash and diarrhoea. Treatment is rest and paracetamol – do not take aspirin or ibuprofen as it increases the likelihood of haemorrhaging. Make sure you see a doctor to be diagnosed and monitored.</string>
    <string name="Goa19">Hepatitis A This food- and water-borne virus infects the liver, causing jaundice (yellow skin and eyes), nausea and lethargy. There is no specific treatment for hepatitis A, you just need to allow time for the liver to heal. All travellers to India should be vaccinated against hepatitis A.</string>
    <string name="Goa20">Hepatitis B This sexually transmitted disease is spread by body fluids and can be prevented by vaccination. The long-term consequences can include liver cancer and cirrhosis.</string>
    <string name="Goa21">Hepatitis E Transmitted through contaminated food and water, hepatitis E has similar symptoms to hepatitis A, but is far less common. It is a severe problem in pregnant women and can result in the death of both mother and baby. There is no commercially available vaccine, and prevention is by following safe eating and drinking guidelines.</string>
    <string name="Goa22">HIV Spread via contaminated body fluids. Avoid unsafe sex, unsterile needles (including in medical facilities) and procedures such as tattoos. The growth rate of HIV in India is one of the highest in the world.</string>
    <string name="Goa23">Influenza Present year-round in the tropics, influenza (flu) symptoms include fever, muscle aches, a runny nose, cough and sore throat. It can be severe in people over the age of 65 or in those with medical conditions such as heart disease or diabetes – vaccination is recommended for these individuals. There is no specific treatment, just rest and paracetamol.</string>
    <string name="Goa24">Japanese B Encephalitis This viral disease is transmitted by mosquitoes and is rare in travellers. Most cases occur in rural areas and vaccination is recommended for travellers spending more than one month outside of cities. There is no treatment, and it may result in permanent brain damage or death. Ask your doctor for further details.</string>
    <string name="Goa25">Rabies This fatal disease is spread by the bite or possibly even the lick of an infected animal most commonly a dog or monkey. You should seek medical advice immediately after any animal bite and commence postexposure treatment. Having pretravel vaccination means the postbite treatment is greatly simplified. If an animal bites you, gently wash the wound with soap and water, and apply iodine-based antiseptic. If you are not prevaccinated you will need to receive rabies immunoglobulin as soon as possible, and this is very difficult to obtain in much of India. Fungal rashes There are two common fungal rashes that affect travellers. The first occurs in moist areas, such as the groin, armpits and between the toes. It starts as a red patch that slowly spreads and is usually itchy. Treatment involves keeping the skin dry, avoiding chafing and using an antifungal cream such as clotrimazole or Lamisil. The second, Tinea versicolor, causes light-coloured patches, most commonly on the back, chest and shoulders. Consult a doctor.</string>
    <string name="Goa26">Cuts and scratches These become easily infected in humid climates. Immediately wash all wounds in clean water and apply antiseptic. If you develop signs of infection (increasing pain and redness), see a doctor.</string>
    <string name="Goa27">Divers and surfers should seek specialised advice before they travel to ensure their medical kit contains treatment for coral cuts and tropical ear infections. Divers should ensure their insurance covers them for decompression illness – get specialised dive insurance through an organisation such as Divers Alert Network (www.danasiapacific.org). Certain medical conditions are incompatible with diving; check with your doctor.</string>


    <string name="Gujrat1">Acute Encephalitis Syndrome (AES) including Japanese Encephalitis (JE) is a group of clinically similar neurologic manifestation caused by several different viruses, bacteria, fungus, parasites, spirochetes, chemical/ toxins etc. The outbreak of JE usually coincides with the monsoon and post monsoon period when the density of mosquitoes increases while encephalitis due to other viruses specially entero-viruses occurs throughout the year as it is a water borne disease. It predominantly affects population below 15 years. There is seasonal and geographical variation in the causative organism. JEV has its endemic zones running along the Gangetic plain including states of UP (east), Bihar, West Bengal and Assam, and parts of Tamil Nadu.</string>
    <string name="Gujrat2">Acute encephalitis syndrome (AES) is characterized by an acute onset of fever and clinical neurological manifestation that includes mental confusion, disorientation, delirium, or coma. Apart from viral encephalitis, severe form of leptospirosis and toxoplasmosis can cause AES. Keeping in mind the wide range of causal agents and the rapid rate of neurological impairment due to pathogenesis, clinicians face the challenge of a small window period between diagnosis and treatment.</string>
    <string name="Gujrat3">1. Increase access to safe drinking water and proper sanitation facilities</string>
    <string name="Gujrat4">2. Improve nutritional status of children at risk of JE/AES</string>
    <string name="Gujrat5">The preventive measures are directed at reducing the vector (mosquito) density. JE vectors are exophillic and endophagic in nature. The risk of transmission increases when the human dwellings and animal sheds particularly piggeries are situated very close to each other. Piggeries may be kept away (4-5 kms) from human dwellings. When they are situated far from each other, the risk of transmission is reduced.</string>
    <string name="Gujrat6">Personal protection against mosquito bites using insecticide treated mosquito nets. Clothing reduces the risk of mosquito biting if the cloth is sufficiently thick or loosely fitting. Long sleeves and trousers with stockings may protect the arms and legs, the preferred sites for mosquito bites. School children should adhere to these practices whenever possible. Household insecticidal products, namely mosquito coils, pyrethrum space spray and aerosols have been used extensively for personal protection against mosquitoes. Electric vaporizer mats and liquid vaporizers are more recent additions which are marketed in practically all urban areas.</string>
    <string name="Gujrat7">Repellents are a common means of personal protection against mosquitoes and other biting insects. These are broadly classified into two categories, natural repellents and chemical repellents. Essential oils from plant extracts are the main natural repellent ingredients, i.e. citronella oil, lemongrass oil and neem oil. The reduction in mosquito breeding requires eco-management, as the role of insecticides is limited.</string>
    <string name="Gujrat8">As per Govt. of India guidelines, 2 doses of JE vaccine have been approved to be included in UIP to be given one along with measles at the age of 9 months and the second with DPT booster at the age of 16-24 months w.e.f. April, 2013.</string>
    <string name="Gujrat9">https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/crimean-congo-haemorrhagic-fever/en/</string>


    <string name="Maharashtra1">Leptospirosis is caused by a bacterium called Leptospira interrogans. The organism is carried by many animals and lives in their kidneys. It ends up in soil and water through their urine. If you’re around soil or water where an infected animal has peed, the germ can invade your body through breaks in your skin, like scratches, open wounds, or dry areas. It can also enter through your nose, mouth, or genitals. It’s hard to get it from another human, though it can be passed through sex or breastfeeding. You’re at risk if you spend a lot of time around animals or in the outdoors</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra2">You usually start showing signs of leptospirosis within 2 weeks, though in some cases, symptoms may not show up for a month or not at all. When the disease does hit, it hits fast. You’ll get a fever. It may spike to 104 F. Other typical symptoms include:</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra3">● Headache</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra4">● Muscle ache</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra5">● Jaundice (yellowing of the skin and eyes)</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra6">● Vomiting</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra7">● Diarrhea</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra8">● Skin rash</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra9">Leptospirosis can be treated with antibiotics , including penicillin and doxycycline . Your doctor may also recommend ibuprofen for fever and muscle pain . The disease should run its course in about a week. But, you may have to go to the hospital if your infection is more severe. Symptoms may include kidney failure, meningitis, and lung problems. You may need to have antibiotics injected into your body, and in very serious cases, the infection could damage your organs.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra10">1. Avoid contaminated water.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra11">2. Keep away from infected animals, especially wild rats</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra12">3. Be aware of your surroundings, especially when you travel</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra13">4. Use disinfectant.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra14">Correcting dehydration is the priority of diarrhea treatment.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra15">Most cases of diarrhea are caused by an infection in the gastrointestinal tract. The microbes responsible for this infection include:</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra16">● bacteria</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra17">● viruses</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra18">● parasitic organisms</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra19">The most commonly identified causes of acute diarrhea in the United States are the bacteria Salmonella, Campylobacter, Shigella, and Shiga-toxin-producing Escherichia coli. Some cases of chronic diarrhea are called "functional" because a clear cause cannot be found. In the developed world, irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) is the most common cause of functional diarrhea.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra20">IBS is a complex of symptoms. There is cramping abdominal pain and altered bowel habits, including diarrhea, constipation , or both. Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) is another cause of chronic diarrhea. It is a term used to describe either ulcerative colitis or Crohn\'s disease. There is often blood in the stool in both conditions.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra21">Mild cases of acute diarrhea may resolve without treatment. Persistent or chronic diarrhea will be diagnosed and any underlying causes will be treated in addition to the symptoms of diarrhea. For all cases of diarrhea, rehydration is key</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra22">Over-the-counter (OTC) antidiarrheal medicines are also available:</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra23">Loperamide, or Imodium, is an antimotility drug that reduces stool passage. Loperamide and Imodium are both available to purchase over-the-counter or online. Bismuth subsalicylate, for example, Pepto-Bismol, reduces diarrheal stool output in adults and children. It can also be used to prevent traveler\'s diarrhea. The can be bought online as well asover-the-counter.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra24">There is some concern that antidiarrheal medications could prolong bacterial infection by reducing the removal of pathogens through stools.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra25">Antibiotics are only used to treat diarrhea caused by a bacterial infection. If the cause is a certain medication, switching to another drug might be possible.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra26">Symptoms of diarrhea can include bloating, thirst, and weight loss. Diarrhea refers to watery stools, but it may be accompanied by other symptoms. These include:</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra27">1. stomach pain</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra28">2. abdominal cramps</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra29">3. bloating</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra30">4. thirst</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra31">5. weight loss</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra32">6. fever</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra33">Diarrhea is a symptom of other conditions, some of which can be serious.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra34">Other possible symptoms are:</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra35">1. blood or pus in the stools</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra36">2. persistent vomiting</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra37">3. dehydration</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra38">https://www.healthline.com/health/amebiasis#treatments</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra39">https://www.medicinenet.com/brucellosis_facts/article.htm#what_is_brucellosis</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra40">https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/313077.php</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra41">Heart disease cases increasing in Maharashtra It came in light that CVDs are increasing in Maharashtra between the age group of 30 - 40 years. Lipid profile and cholesterol levels are seen high amongst men and women in the age bracket of 45-50 years.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra42">It was observed that women between the age group of 40 - 60 are getting more prone to CVDs because of drastic lifestyle changes. Inactive lifestyle, poor eating habits and lack of exercise are leading factors behind the risk of CVDs. It was witnessed that women often overlook symptoms and discomfort pertaining to heart diseases, and rarely consult an expert. Even if they do opt for expert’s consultation, more often they will discontinue the treatment as soon as they get symptomatic relief.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra43">Heart diseases are taking a toll on women and children in India. The susceptibility ratio of men to women is 3:2 in younger age group, but after menopause the ratio becomes 1:1.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra44">Reasons could be...</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra45">As women mature with age, their health related needs change, as do their preventative care requirements. Besides lifestyle modification, preventive health check-ups are very useful in early detection of all types of illnesses and risk factors.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra46">Mental and physical stress is one of the leading causes of heart diseases among female as now a day’s most of them are managing office and home together, which further leads to less rest and minimum sleeping hours. Contrary to conventional belief that ‘pre-menstrual women are completely safe from heart ailments it has been noticed the menstruating population is falling prey to cardiovascular diseases.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra47">The increasing prevalence of diseases like hypertension, dyslipidemia, diabetes and obesity has led to an increase in the burden of cardiovascular diseases in India. Physical inactivity, increased use of tobacco, and genetic make-up, makes us more prone to falling prey to heart diseases. Experts believe that the 80 % to 90% of risk factor for CVDs can be prevented by controlling risk factors like tobacco consumption, alcohol abuse and following a healthy diet, control over high blood pressure, cholesterol, timely and regular preventive health check-ups.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra48">Regular preventive health checkups are the easiest and most effective way out to catch heart disease early in their origin so that they can be managed and treated well.</string>
    <string name="Maharashtra49">Keeping your heart healthy and fit is so important and for which you need a regular checkup. It will help you in understanding the know-how of your health with which you can avoid any possible health complication by taking proper medication and treatment. Going for the essential heart checkup on a regular basis will provide a thorough analysis of your heart so that you can start immediate treatment if necessary.</string>


    <string name="Rajasthan">Dengue fever, also known as breakbone fever, is a mosquito-borne infection that can lead to a severe flu-like illness. It is caused by four different viruses and spread by Aedes mosquitoes.Symptoms range from mild to severe. Severe symptoms include dengue shock syndrome (DSS) and dengue hemorrhagic fever (DHF). These usually require hospitalization. There are currently no vaccines. The best method of prevention is to avoid mosquito bites. Treatment is possible if diagnosis occurs before the patient develops DSS or DHF. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) estimate that 400 million people are infected each year. Dengue fever is rare in the United States (U.S.), but around 100 cases are reported each year, mostly among people traveling from outside the country. Outbreaks have occurred in Texas, Florida, and Hawaii. </string>
    <string name="Rajasthan1">Here are some key points about dengue fever </string>
    <string name="Rajasthan2">1. Dengue is transmitted by the mosquitoes Aedes aegypti and Aedes albopictus, which are found throughout the world.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan3">2. Around 2.5 billion people, or 40 percent of the world\'s population, live in areas where there is a risk of dengue transmission.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan4">3. Dengue is endemic in at least 100 countries in Asia, the Pacific, the Americas, Africa, and the Caribbean.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan5">4. Symptoms usually begin 4 to 7 days after the mosquito bite and typically last 3 to 10 days.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan6">5. Effective treatment is possible if a clinical diagnosis is made early.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan7">Symptoms can appear up to 7 days after being bitten by the mosquito that carries the virus.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan8">1. aching muscles and joints</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan9">2. body rash that can disappear and then reappear</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan10">3. high fever</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan11">4. intense headache</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan12">5. pain behind the eyes</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan13">6. vommiting and feeling nauseous</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan14">Dengue is a virus, so there is no specific treatment or cure. However, intervention can help, depending on how severe the disease is. For milder forms, treatment includes:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan15">1. Preventing dehydration: A high fever and vomiting can dehydrate the body. The person should drink clean water, ideally bottled rather than tap water. Rehydration salts can also help replace fluids and minerals.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan16">2. Painkillers, such as Tylenol or paracetamol: These can help lower fever and ease pain.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan17">3. Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), such as aspirin or ibuprofen, are not advised, as they can increase the risk of internal bleeding.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan18">More severe forms of dengue fever may need:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan19">1. intravenous (IV) fluid supplementation, or drip, if the person cannot take fluids by mouth</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan20">2. blood transfusion, for patients with severe dehydration</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan21">Hospitalization will allow the individual to be properly monitored, in case symptoms get worse.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan22">Clothing: Reduce the amount of skin exposed by wearing long pants, long-sleeved shirts, and socks, tucking pant legs into shoes or socks, and wearing a hat.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan23">Mosquito repellents: Use a repellent with at least 10 percent concentration of diethyltoluamide (DEET), or a higher concentration for longer lengths of exposure. Avoid using DEET on young children.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan24">Mosquito traps and nets: Nets treated with insecticide are more effective, otherwise the mosquito can bite through the net if the person is standing next to it. The insecticide will kill mosquitoes and other insects, and it will repel insects from entering the room.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan25">Door and window screens: Structural barriers, such as screens or netting, can keep mosquitos out.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan26">Avoid scents: Heavily scented soaps and perfumes may attract mosquitos.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan27">Camping gear: Treat clothes, shoes, and camping gear with permethrin, or purchase clothes that have been pretreated.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan28">Timing: Try to avoid being outside at dawn, dusk, and early evening.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan29">Stagnant water: The Aedes mosquito breeds in clean, stagnant water. Checking for and removing stagnant water can help reduce the risk.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan30">The chikungunya virus infects humans through the bite of a mosquito. It causes fever and joint pain. It is rarely fatal, but the symptoms can be severe, long-lasting, and debilitating. Once considered a disease of the tropics, cases have now been documented in more than one quarter of the countries on earth. This article will discuss the chikungunya virus, its causes, symptoms, treatment, and diagnosis - it will also cover ways to avoid the virus. The chikungunya virus is predominantly transmitted by a bite from an infected female mosquito. In general, it is not considered contagious; however, in rare cases, the virus can be transmitted through contact with an infected individual\'s blood.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan31">Fast facts on chikungunya virus:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan32">1. The word "chikungunya" means "to walk bent".</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan33">2. The major symptoms are fever and joint pain.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan34">3. Chikungunya can only be definitively diagnosed by a blood test.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan35">4. There are no vaccines for chikungunya.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan36">The virus causes a fever that lasts a few days and joint pain that can last weeks or months. The symptoms of chikungunya virus are similar to those of other diseases such as dengue fever. The symptoms normally appear just a few days after a mosquito has bitten an individual. The most common symptoms are:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan37">1. fever (sometimes as high as 104 °F)</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan38">2. joint pain</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan39">3. headache</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan40">4. muscle pain</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan41">5. rash</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan42">6. swelling around the joints</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan43">7. Less commonly, symptoms can be accompanied by a maculopapular rash (similar to measles or heat rash), conjunctivitis, nausea, and vomiting.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan44">The virus is rarely fatal, but the symptoms can be severe and disabling. Most patients recover from the fever within a week, but the joint pain has been known to persist for months. Even after 1 year, 20 percent of patients report recurring joint pain.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan45">There are no specific drugs to treat chikungunya; doctors simply recommend rest and plenty of fluids.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan46">Over-the-counter medications will help ease fever and joint pain. These include:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan47">1. naproxen</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan48">2. ibuprofen</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan49">3. acetaminophen</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan50">For longer-lasting aches, physiotherapy may be helpful.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan51">Seeing as the major mode of chikungunya transmission is by mosquito bite, the best methods of prevention involve minimizing contact with mosquitos. Steps that can be taken to prevent chikungunya include:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan52">1. Using insect repellent containing DEET (N, N-Diethyl-meta-toluamide) or picaridin on skin and clothing.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan53">2. Wearing clothing that covers the whole body.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan54">3. Staying indoors as much as possible, especially during early morning and late afternoon.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan55">4. Avoiding traveling to areas experiencing outbreaks.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan56">5. Using products containing oil of lemon eucalyptus or PMD (p-Menthane-3,8-diol) can be effective.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan57">6. Using air-conditioning - this deters mosquitos from entering rooms.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan58">7. Sleeping under a mosquito net.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan59">8. Using mosquito coils and insecticide vaporizers.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan60">Although chikungunya is very rarely fatal, the symptoms are distressing and can be long-lived. Avoiding mosquitos is key. </string>
    <string name="Rajasthan61">The Zika virus is mosquito-borne and spread by the Aedes mosquito; the same species that transmits Dengue, Chikungunya, and Yellow Fever.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan62">The virus is transmitted when an infected person is bitten by a mosquito, which then bites other people. It can also spread from a pregnant woman to her baby. In addition, the virus has also been found to spread through sexual intercourse and some studies observed the presence of the virus in the saliva, blood, urine, and eye fluid of an infected person.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan63">Though most infected people won’t show any symptoms, a few (about 1 in 5) may display the following symptoms, which could range from mild to severe:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan64">1. Fever</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan65">2. Headache</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan66">3. Rash</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan67">4. Joint pain</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan68">5. Muscle pain</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan69">6. Pink eye (conjunctivitis)</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan70">Symptoms may show up any time from 3-14 days after a mosquito bite and can remain for several days to a week.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan71">During a pregnancy, the virus can cause serious birth defects of the brain, such as microcephaly (babies born with abnormally small heads), brain damage, and Guillain-Barré syndrome (where healthy nerve cells are attacked by one’s own immune system). In addition, it could also cause miscarriage and stillbirth. Hence, pregnant women are advised to steer clear of areas prone to Zika virus risks.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan72">There is no vaccine or medicine/treatment for Zika.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan73">The only sure-fire preventive method is to avoid getting bitten by mosquitoes, period. Since we can’t tell which mosquitoes are vectors and which are not, the only option is to block them all. This can be achieved by taking the following steps:</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan74">1.Use Goodknight Patches, which are a safe and highly effective solution for keeping mosquitoes at bay. Made from herbal products, it’s completely safe for pregnant women and small children. These can be applied to clothes or items nearby to create a mosquito-free zone for up to eight hours.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan75">2.Stay indoors and ensure the doors and windows of your home have screens to thwart these pests.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan76">3.Wear suitable clothing that covers most of your body, such as long-sleeved shirts, and long pants with socks and shoes.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan77">4.Keep your surroundings clean, and pay special attention to areas where mosquitoes can breed, such as standing water, flower pots, old tires etc.</string>
    <string name="Rajasthan78">To conclude, the Zika virus can only be prevented by preventing mosquito bites. So, take appropriate steps now to keep you and your baby safe and healthy.</string>


    <!--DAMAN AND DIU Done with rajasthan only -->


    <string name="DadarNH1">Mumps is a contagious disease caused by a virus that passes from one person to another through saliva, nasal secretions, and close personal contact. The condition primarily affects the salivary glands, also called the parotid glands. These glands are responsible for producing saliva. There are three sets of salivary glands on each side of your face, located behind and below your ears. The hallmark symptom of mumps is swelling of the salivary glands.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH2">Symptoms of mumps usually appear within two weeks of exposure to the virus. Flu-like symptoms may be the first to appear, including:</string>
    <string name="DadarNH3">1. Fatigue</string>
    <string name="DadarNH4">2. Body aches</string>
    <string name="DadarNH5">3. Headache</string>
    <string name="DadarNH6">4. Loss of appetite</string>
    <string name="DadarNH7">5. Low-grade fever</string>
    <string name="DadarNH8">A high fever of 103°F (39°C) and swelling of the salivary glands follow over the next few days. The glands may not all swell at once. More commonly, they swell and become painful periodically. You are most likely to pass the mumps virus to another person from the time you come into contact with the virus to when your parotid glands swell. Most people who contract mumps show symptoms of the virus. However, some people have no or very few symptoms.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH9">Because mumps is a virus, it doesn’t respond to antibiotics or other medications. However, you can treat the symptoms to make yourself more comfortable while you’re sick. These include: </string>
    <string name="DadarNH10">1.Rest when you feel weak or tired.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH11">2.Take over-the-counter pain relievers, such as acetaminophen and ibuprofen, to bring down your fever.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH12">3.Soothe swollen glands by applying ice packs.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH13">4.Drink plenty of fluids to avoid dehydration due to fever.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH14">5.Eat a soft diet of soup, yogurt, and other foods that aren’t hard to chew (chewing may be painful when your glands are swollen).</string>
    <string name="DadarNH15">6.Avoid acidic foods and beverages that may cause more pain in your salivary glands.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH16">You can usually return to work or school about one week after a doctor diagnoses your mumps, if you feel up to it. By this point, you’re no longer contagious. Mumps usually runs its course in a couple of weeks. Ten days into your illness, you should be feeling better. Most people who get mumps can’t contract the disease a second time. Having the virus once protects you against becoming infected again.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH17">Vaccination can prevent mumps. Most infants and children receive a vaccine for measles, mumps, and rubella (MMR) at the same time. The first MMR shot is generally given between the ages of 12 and 15 months at a routine well-child visit. A second vaccination is necessary for school-aged children between 4 and 6 years old. With two doses, the mumps vaccine is approximately 88 percent effective. The rate of effectivenessTrusted Source of only one dose is about 78 percent. </string>
    <string name="DadarNH18">Adults who were born before 1957 and haven’t yet contracted mumps may wish to be vaccinated. Those who work in a high-risk environment, such as a hospital or school, should always be vaccinated against mumps.</string>
    <string name="DadarNH19">However, people who have compromised immune systems, are allergic to gelatin or neomycin, or are pregnant, shouldn’t receive the MMR vaccine. Consult your family doctor about an immunization schedule for you and your children.</string>


    <string name="Delhi1">Common problems-The hazardous air quality also poses serious health risks, especially for people who already suffer from some kind of respiratory problems. Any person exposed to the serious conditions of air pollution are at a risk of developing various health problems. However, the danger is higher among babies, young children, elderly ppeople as well as individuals suffering from apny type of respiratory problems such as COPD or asthma need to take extra precautions. Even a small increase in dust levels and concentration can aggravate the symptoms of asthma, COPD, and many other respiratory problems. The pollution levels also pose a higher risk of developing long-term health issues.</string>
    <string name="Delhi2">COPD- https://www.healthline.com/health/copd</string>
    <string name="Delhi3">Tips to stay healthy</string>
    <string name="Delhi4">https://www.timesnownews.com/health/article/delhi-air-pollution-10-tips-to-stay-safe-and-healthy/121182</string>


    <string name="JK">Asthma
https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.livescience.com/amp/41264-asthma-symptoms-treatment.h
tml
Tb https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/8856.php

    Vitamin a deficiency
https://www.merckmanuals.com/professional/nutritional-disorders/vitamin-deficiency,-dependen
cy,-and-toxicity/vitamin-a-deficiency</string>


    <string name="UP1">Diarrheal diseases and tb more commonly reported due to less development.</string>
    <string name="UP2">Kala-azar is a parasitic disease caused by Leishmania donovani transmitted by sandflies
Phlebotomus argentipes. The disease is prevalent among socio-economically poorer sections of
the society living in rural areas. The disease is chronic and if not treated, leads to death.
Kala-azar is endemic in Bihar, Jharkhand, West Bengal and parts of Uttar Pradesh. The Central
Government initiated Kala-azar control Programme from 1990-91 incorporating assistance for
procurement of insecticides and anti-leishmanial drugs. The National Health Policy 2002
envisaged a goal of Kala-azar Elimination by the year 2010. To pursue the goal of elimination of
Kalaazar by the year 2010, the Govt of India is providing 100% support to endemic states since
2003, apart from regular technical guidance. Timely and quality Indoor Residual Spraying with
DDT for vector control, complete treatment of patients as well as intensive social mobilization is
being stressed upon. Govt. of India has accelerated the Kala-azar elimination by taking the
following renewed efforts.</string>
    <string name="UP3">Intensification of Kala-azar Case Search through Kala-azar Fortnight.
Patient Coding Scheme initiated in all treatment centres to ensure complete treatment
compliance.
Introduction of rapid diagnostic test (rk39) and oral drug miltefosine for early detection of
Kala-azar and better treatment compliance.
Identification of Kala-azar activist amongst the affected communities and mobilization of the
community for early reporting and treatment compliance.</string>


    <string name="Punjab1">Dengue on the rise (pehle wale me se le lio data)</string>
    <string name="Punjab2">Cancer causes unknown but speculated to be contaminated water and excessive use of
chemical fertilizers. https://www.medicinenet.com/cancer/article.htm#cancer_facts</string>
    <string name="Punjab3">Hepatitis c
https://www.webmd.com/hepatitis/digestive-diseases-hepatitis-c</string>

    <string name="Uttrakhand1">No specific disease</string>
    <string name="Uttrakhand2">Meningitis https://www.healthline.com/health/meningitis#treatments</string>
    <string name="Uttrakhand3">Leprosy</string>


    <string name="Haryana">Cancer</string>
    <string name="Haryana1">Heart disease due to more salt intake like high bp</string>


    <string name="Jharkhand">Three most common diagnosis were upper respiratory infections, acute gastroenteritis including water-borne diseases, and anemia. Treatment given to these patients comprised of mostly of antipyretic, analgesic, and antimicrobial agents. Most common drug prescribed was paracetamol for fever. Other common drugs prescribed were amoxicillin/clavulanic acid, chloroquine, artemisin derivative, doxycycline, co-trimoxazole, miltefosine, cephalexin, ceftriaxone sodium, cefixime, oral rehydration salts, ranitidine, omeprazole, pantoprazole, metronidazole, albendazole, ondansetron, diclofenac sodium, piroxicam, ibuprofen, diphenhydramine, codeine-sulfate, amlodipine, ramipril, hydrochlorothiazide, atenolol, salbutamol, etophyline, metformin, glimepiride, fluoxetine, flavoxate, tamsulosin, iron-folic acid, etc. The fact that three or more drugs are given in most of the prescriptions, can be justified due to multiple morbidity and the severity of disease than to irresponsible prescribing. The Jharkhand state is highly endemic for malaria contributing about 7% of total malaria cases in the country. Othe vector-borne diseases prevalent in the state are filariasis, kala-azar and dengue. Most of patients still suffer due to transmission of air-borne diseases like URIs (with inluenza like illness) and TB, or water-borne diseases like acute gastroenteritis and typhoid, or fomite-borne infectious diseases like scabies and tinea. In states like Jharkhand, patients suffering with congenital haemolytic anaemia are  more. The programme organized at the new auditorium of RIMS bearing 1000 seat capacity was inaugurated by Governor Dr Syed Ahmed. A person suffering with a gene disorder is known as carrier. It is obvious the child of this carrier would have a gene disorder. If at the time of conception, a baby is detected with this ailment while undergoing sonography, there are 50 to 60 percent chances of prevention. The treatment after birth demands regular blood supply after every three weeks to the child for effective growth which rounds upto lakhs.There are around eight of ten thousand genetic diseases in the world. There is a requirement of New Born Screening centres at every hospital in the country. There are only few such centres in some States where a new born baby is diagnosed with a small blood test within 24 hours of delivery. The diagnosis charges only 25 paise. If this is done, then health ailments like hypothyroid, congenital, adrenal hypothesis and sickle cell anaemia can be treated right from the beginning stage. </string>


    <string name="Odisha">Three most common diagnosis were upper respiratory infections, acute gastroenteritis including water-borne diseases, and anemia. Treatment given to these patients comprised of mostly of antipyretic, analgesic, and antimicrobial agents. Most common drug prescribed was paracetamol for fever. Other common drugs prescribed were amoxicillin/clavulanic acid, chloroquine, artemisin derivative, doxycycline, co-trimoxazole, miltefosine, cephalexin, ceftriaxone sodium, cefixime, oral rehydration salts, ranitidine, omeprazole, pantoprazole, metronidazole, albendazole, ondansetron, diclofenac sodium, piroxicam, ibuprofen, diphenhydramine, codeine-sulfate, amlodipine, ramipril, hydrochlorothiazide, atenolol, salbutamol, etophyline, metformin, glimepiride, fluoxetine, flavoxate, tamsulosin, iron-folic acid, etc. The fact that three or more drugs are given in most of the prescriptions, can be justified due to multiple morbidity and the severity of disease than to irresponsible prescribing. The Jharkhand state is highly endemic for malaria contributing about 7% of total malaria cases in the country. Othe vector-borne diseases prevalent in the state are filariasis, kala-azar and dengue. Most of patients still suffer due to transmission of air-borne diseases like URIs (with inluenza like illness) and TB, or water-borne diseases like acute gastroenteritis and typhoid, or fomite-borne infectious diseases like scabies and tinea. In states like Jharkhand, patients suffering with congenital haemolytic anaemia are  more. The programme organized at the new auditorium of RIMS bearing 1000 seat capacity was inaugurated by Governor Dr Syed Ahmed. A person suffering with a gene disorder is known as carrier. It is obvious the child of this carrier would have a gene disorder. If at the time of conception, a baby is detected with this ailment while undergoing sonography, there are 50 to 60 percent chances of prevention. The treatment after birth demands regular blood supply after every three weeks to the child for effective growth which rounds upto lakhs.There are around eight of ten thousand genetic diseases in the world. There is a requirement of New Born Screening centres at every hospital in the country. There are only few such centres in some States where a new born baby is diagnosed with a small blood test within 24 hours of delivery. The diagnosis charges only 25 paise. If this is done, then health ailments like hypothyroid, congenital, adrenal hypothesis and sickle cell anaemia can be treated right from the beginning stage. </string>


    <string name="MadhP1">Tuberculosis (TB) is a potentially serious infectious disease that mainly affects your lungs. The bacteria that cause tuberculosis are spread from one person to another through tiny droplets released into the air via coughs and sneezes. Once rare in developed countries, tuberculosis infections began increasing in 1985, partly because of the emergence of HIV, the virus that causes AIDS. HIV weakens a person\'s immune system so it can\'t fight the TB germs. In the United States, because of stronger control programs, tuberculosis began to decrease again in 1993, but remains a concern. Many strains of tuberculosis resist the drugs most used to treat the disease. People with active tuberculosis must take several types of medications for many months to eradicate the infection and prevent development of antibiotic resistance. Signs and symptoms of active TB include: Coughing that lasts three or more weeks, Coughing up blood, Chest pain, or pain with breathing or coughing, Unintentional weight loss, Fatigue, Fever, Night sweats, Chills.</string>
    <string name="MadhP2">A group of diseases that result in too much sugar in the blood (high blood glucose). Diabetes Mellitus Signs and Symptoms:</string>
    <string name="MadhP3">•	Frequent urination.</string>
    <string name="MadhP4">•	Excessive thirst.</string>
    <string name="MadhP5">•	Unexplained weight loss.</string>
    <string name="MadhP6">•	Extreme hunger.</string>
    <string name="MadhP7">•	Sudden vision changes</string>
    <string name="MadhP8">•	Tingling or numbness in the hands or feet.</string>
    <string name="MadhP9">•	Feeling very tired much of the time.</string>
    <string name="MadhP10">• Very dry skin.</string>
    <string name="MadhP11">One of the emerging disease in Madhya Pradesh is cancer. ancer is a group of diseases involving abnormal cell growth with the potential to invade or spread to other parts of the body. These contrast with benign tumors, which do not spread. Possible signs and symptoms include a lump, abnormal bleeding, prolonged cough, unexplained weight loss, and a change in bowel movements. While these symptoms may indicate cancer, they can also have other causes. Over 100 types of cancers affect humans.</string>


    <string name="AndamanN">Hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) is characterized by rashes or vesicular lesions mainly on the hands, feet and mouth. It usually affects children and is most commonly caused by Enterovirus-A (EV-A) species, including Coxsackievirus-A16 (CV-A16) and Enterovirus-71 (EV-71) . Usually, HFMD caused due to CV-A16 is less severe disease as compared to that caused by EV-71.</string>


    <string name="Lakshdweep">Asthma is a condition in which your airways narrow and swell and produce extra mucus. This can make breathing difficult and trigger coughing, wheezing and shortness of breath.
Asthma symptoms vary from person to person. You may have infrequent asthma attacks, have symptoms only at certain times — such as when exercising — or have symptoms all the time.
</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep1">Asthma signs and symptoms include:</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep2">1.Shortness of breath</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep3">2.Chest tightness or pain</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep4">3.Trouble sleeping caused by shortness of breath, coughing or wheezing</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep5">4.A whistling or wheezing sound when exhaling (wheezing is a common sign of asthma in children)</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep6">5.Coughing or wheezing attacks that are worsened by a respiratory virus, such as a cold or the flu</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep7">Signs that your asthma is probably worsening include:</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep8">1.Asthma signs and symptoms that are more frequent and bothersome</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep9">2.Increasing difficulty breathing (measurable with a peak flow meter, a device used to check how well your lungs are working)</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep10">3.The need to use a quick-relief inhaler more often</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep11"> play two roles in your immune system:</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep12">1. Destroying foreign substances. Eosinophils can consume foreign substances. For example, they fight substances related to parasitic infection that have been flagged for destruction by your immune system.
</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep13">2. Regulating inflammation. Eosinophils help promote inflammation, which plays a beneficial role in isolating and controlling a disease site. But sometimes inflammation may be greater than is necessary, which can lead to troublesome symptoms or even tissue damage. For example, eosinophils play a key role in the symptoms of asthma and allergies, such as hay fever. Other immune system disorders also can contribute to ongoing (chronic) inflammation.
</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep14">Eosinophilia occurs when a large number of eosinophils are recruited to a specific site in your body or when the bone marrow produces too many eosinophils. This can be caused by a variety of factors, including:</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep15">1.Parasitic and fungal diseases</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep16">2.Allergies including allergies to medications or food</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep17">3.Adrenal conditions</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep18">4.Skin disorders</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep19">5.Toxins</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep20">6.Autoimmune disorders</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep21">7.Endocrine disorders</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep22">8.Tumors</string>
    <string name="Lakshdweep23">Amoebiasis is a common cause of diarrhoea in infants in low-income countries. Amoebiasis also causes colitis that can present with diarrhoea and/or dysentery that can be acute or last more than 1 week. Abdominal tenderness and weight loss are common with amoebic colitis.
Amoebic liver abscess presents with right upper quadrant pain. May not present with diarrhoea, but will usually have a preceding history of diarrhoea.
Rare cause of brain abscess.
Most patients will have travelled to or resided in an endemic area in the 12 months preceding presentation.
Diagnosis is confirmed by detection of Entamoeba histolytica antigen or DNA in stool or antibodies against the parasite in serum.
Treatment is with nitroimidazoles (including metronidazole or tinidazole) followed by luminal agents such as paromomycin or diloxanide furoate to prevent relapse.
</string>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Profile</string>
</resources>
